This is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain for more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this
recording by J Hall The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by L. Frank Baum Introduction
Folklore, legends, myths and fairy tales have followed childhood throughout the
ages, for every healthy youngster has a wholesome and instinctive love for
stories fantastic, marvelous and manifestly unreal. The winged fairies of
Grimm and Andersen have brought more happiness to childish hearts than all
other human creations. Yet the old-time fairy tale, having served for generations,
may now be classed as “historical” in the children’s library; for the time has come
for a series of newer “wonder tales” in which the stereotyped genie, dwarf and
fairy are eliminated, together with all the horrible and blood-curdling
incidents devised by their authors to point a fearsome moral to each tale.
Modern education includes morality; therefore the modern child seeks only
entertainment in its wonder tales and gladly dispenses with all disagreeable
incident. Having this thought in mind, the story of “The Wonderful Wizard of Oz” was
written solely to police children of today. It aspires to being a modernized
fairy tale, in which the wonderment and joy are retained and the heartaches and
nightmares are left out. L. Frank Baum Chicago, April, 1900 this is a librivox